Don't move!
Nie ruszaj się!
It's not her?
To nie ona?
It wasn't her.
To nie ona.
But this one's a monster, too, right?
Ale on też jest potworem, prawda?
Hang on a second!
Poczekaj!
What is it, Migi?
Czym on jest?
He still has his human brain.
Nadal ma ludzki mózg.
What?
Co?
Now, this is pretty unusual.
To dość niezwykłe.
Just the hand, huh?
Tylko ręka?
How is that a human brain?
To ma być ludzki mózg?
No, he's right!
On ma rację!
It's really--
To naprawdę…
It's the real deal, see?
Jestem prawdziwy, widzicie?
It's true, Shinichi.
To prawda, Shinichi.
His brain is intact.
Ma nienaruszony mózg.
From the lower half of his face to the front of his neck
Dolna część twarzy i przód szyi.
and perhaps down to his chest is where…
Pewnie też klatka piersiowa. To tam…
That's right.
Zgadza się.
So we're in the same boat!
Jedziemy na tym samym wózku!
AUTHOR: HITOSHI IWAAKI
AUTOR: HITOSHI IWAAKI
DARK NIGHT'S PASSING
CIEMNA NOC PRZEMINIE
A year after I got married, my wife ran off.
Rok po ślubie moja żona uciekła.
She didn't say why,
Nie powiedziała dlaczego,
but I think she got sick of my easygoing, indecisive personality.
ale chyba miała dość tego, że jestem taki spokojny i niezdecydowany.
But I didn't have the guts to actually kill myself.
Nie miałem odwagi, żeby się zabić.
It's beautiful.
Piękne.
A snake?
Wąż?
Go away! Shoo!
Odejdź! Uciekaj!
And then…
A potem…
I'll finish.
Ja opowiem.
Your right hand should have some recollection of this, too.
Twoja prawa ręka pewnie też to pamięta.
At first, "Take over the brain" is our only goal,
Naszym celem jest przejęcie mózgu,
so I was working my way toward the brain, but…
więc chciałem się do niego dostać, ale…
What's going on?
Co się dzieje?
The host is not breathing.
Gospodarz nie oddycha.
This body will soon die.
To ciało niedługo umrze.
Forget taking his brain.
Nie przejmę jego mózgu.
I'm about to die with him.
Umrę razem z nim.
I merged with his body as it approached a near-death state
Połączyłem się z jego ciałem, gdy już umierał, i…
I see. Interesting.
Rozumiem. To ciekawe.
So, yeah, that's how I…
A więc tak…
LET ME TALK, TOO
DAJ MI COŚ POWIEDZIEĆ
When I give you control over my upper body,
Gdy oddaję ci kontrolę nad moim górnym ciałem,
I can't be as dynamic when I talk!
to strasznie zanudzasz!
Shut up!
Zamknij się!
But this sure was a surprise.
Byłem bardzo zaskoczony.
When this guy suddenly said one of his own kind was coming closer,
Gdy powiedział, że zbliża się ktoś z jego gatunku,
I wasn't sure what kind of monster I'd see.
zastanawiałem się, jakiego potwora zobaczę.
But it was a relief to see you.
Ulżyło mi, że to ty.
Man, I didn't know there were others like me!
Nie wiedziałem, że tacy jak ja istnieją!
So, tell me.
Powiedz.
What's the story behind your right hand?
Jak to się stało, że masz taką rękę?
Yeah, tell us.
Powiedz nam.
Okay.
Dobrze.
But before I do that, can we go somewhere else?
Ale możemy pójść w inne miejsce?
I'm Izumi Shinichi.
Jestem Izumi Shinichi.
This is Migi.
To jest Migi.
It's just that we need to stay close to a certain location.
Chcę być blisko pewnego miejsca.
Oh, I'm Uda Mamoru.
Nazywam się Uda Mamoru.
You can just call him Parasite.
A na niego mówcie „Parasite”.
Yeah, Parasite's just fine.
Tak, pasuje mi to.
He's gone.
Zniknął.
Where did he go?
Dokąd poszedł?
That's horrible. It's too cruel!
To straszne! Takie okrutne!
And that's why you've stayed near this hospital all this time.
Dlatego trzymasz się blisko szpitala.
It must be so hard on you.
Pewnie ci ciężko.
I don't think I could bear it.
Ja bym tego nie zniósł.
Right.
Jasne.
Why does this guy cry so much?
Dlaczego on tyle płacze?
I really don't get humans.
Nie rozumiem ludzi.
I sometimes feel the same way.
Czasami mam tak samo.
Migi has a very proper way of speaking, doesn't he?
Migi jest bardzo elokwentny, prawda?
Huh? Oh.
Słucham?
I think it's probably because he's read so many books.
Pewnie dlatego, że dużo czyta.
I learned human speech from TV.
Ja nauczyłem się mowy z telewizji.
He loves watching movies, see, and he's always crying over them.
On uwielbia oglądać filmy. Ciągle na nich płacze.
Crying's pretty unique to humans, huh?
Tylko ludzie płaczą, prawda?
Just be quiet for a second!
Zamknij się na chwilę!
I work at a hotel in the next town over.
Pracuję w hotelu w sąsiednim mieście.
I'll let you know the moment this "enemy" of yours shows up.
Dam ci znać, gdy pojawi się twój wróg.
Let us help you!
Pomożemy ci!
I mean, you're the first person like me I've ever met!
Jesteś pierwszą taką osobą, którą spotkałem!
He really does cry a lot.
Naprawdę dużo płacze.
But I'm also glad.
Ale cieszę się.
I didn't know there were others like me.
Nie wiedziałem, że tacy jak ja istnieją. Że mam sojuszników!
Shinichi.
Shinichi!
What do you want at this time of night?
Czego chcesz o tej porze?
It's important.
To ważne.
I thought about telling you during the day,
Chciałem wcześniej o tym powiedzieć, ale pojawił się Uda i jego pasożyt.
Remember what happened, Shinichi.
Pamiętaj, co się stało.
You ran at the speed of an Olympic athlete
Biegłeś jak sportowiec olimpijski
and leapt more than three meters high.
i skoczyłeś trzy metry w górę.
What?
Co?
You didn't realize it?
Nie wiedziałeś?
Then allow me to explain.
To ci wyjaśnię.
First, about my own body.
Najpierw moje ciało.
This requires practice, you know.
To wymaga praktyki.
If I just split in two,
Jeśli się podzielę na dwie części,
each of us is capable of thought and speech.
każda część może myśleć i mówić.
But if I split into fragments that are too small,
Ale jeśli podzielę się na zbyt małe części,
our intelligence is diminished
nasza inteligencja spadnie i nie będziemy mogli myśleć
much less rejoining the others.
ani przyłączać się do innych.
We'd shrivel up and die in no time.
Skurczymy się i umrzemy.
Whoa.
Rety.
So, when I split into multiple selves, I issue a mental directive in advance.
Gdy się dzielę, wydaję rozporządzenie.
A mantra, if you will.
Taką mantrę.
"Come back together as one."
„Połączmy się w całość”.
Okay. I see.
Rozumiem.
However, there are places where even the smallest
Jednak są miejsca, w których przeżyje najmniejsza część mnie.
Somewhere with a constant flow of fresh blood.
Gdzie jest stały dopływ świeżej krwi.
Namely, anywhere within your body.
Czyli gdziekolwiek w twoim ciele.
My…
W moim…
Wait, Migi, you--
Migi, ty…
That's right.
Zgadza się.
The Migi who's talking to you right now
Migi, który z tobą rozmawia,
only accounts for about 70% of my original self.
to tylko 70% prawdziwego mnie.
When I closed the hole in your heart,
Gdy zamknąłem dziurę w twoim sercu,
I issued a directive to return to your right hand via your bloodstream,
wydałem rozporządzenie, żeby wrócić do twojej ręki,
but your restored heart was much stronger than I'd expected,
ale twoje serce było silniejsze, niż się spodziewałem,
so my fragments scattered throughout your body.
więc moje części rozprzestrzeniły się po twoim ciele.
They have become so small that I can no longer communicate with them.
Są takie małe, że nie mogę się z nimi komunikować.
What the…
Cholera…
And here, I thought nothing could possibly surprise me anymore.
A już myślałem, że nic mnie nie zaskoczy.
If you didn't exhibit any physiological changes,
Gdybyś nie przeszedł przemiany,
I was going to keep quiet about it.
nic bym o tym nie powiedział.
Migi.
Migi.
Yes?
Tak?
You said throughout my body.
Jesteś w moim ciele.
Does that include my brain?
W mózgu też?
I don't know.
Nie wiem.
But the fragments are not conscious
Ale te części nie mają świadomości.
and I doubt they would bother to infiltrate capillaries.
Wątpię, że będą chciały wejść w naczynia włosowate.
-Do you have some concern? -No, it's nothing major.
Martwisz się czymś?
I may just be imagining it.
Coś mi się ubzdurało.
At that time,
Czułem, że moje serce eksploduje z emocji, które we mnie są,
but I still couldn't cry.
ale nie mogłem płakać.
It was the same earlier today, too.
Dzisiaj było tak samo.
Uda-san cried like a baby when he met
Uda-san płakał jak bóbr, gdy pierwszy raz zobaczył podobnego do siebie…
Crying's pretty unique to humans, huh?
Tylko ludzie płaczą, prawda?
The hole in my heart, huh?
Dziura w moim sercu?
Maki-chan.
Maki-chan.
Oh, you knew I was here?
Wiedziałeś, że tu jestem?
Do I look like a normal human being to you?
Według ciebie wyglądam jak normalny człowiek?
Huh? Sure. Why?
Co? Jasne, że tak. A co?
Jeez, what's your deal?
Rety, co z tobą?
You get your answer and that's it?
Dostałeś odpowiedź i tyle?
You don't tell me anything.
Ty nic mi nie mówisz.
Huh?
Co?
Back on the boat and now, too,
Na promie i teraz.
you have this terrible look on your face sometimes, like…
Masz czasami taką straszną minę…
like you're crying inside!
jakbyś w środku płakał!
It makes me worry about you.
Martwię się o ciebie.
Sorry.
Przepraszam.
Just forget it!
Nieważne!
It's Uda-san.
Dzwoni Uda-san.
It's here! A parasite!
Jest tutaj! Pasożyt!
We think it must be your enemy!
Ty chyba twój wróg!
And she's heading straight here?
Idzie w waszą stronę?
No, she seems to have noticed us and is coming closer.
Zauważyła nas i się zbliża.
We'll do our best to keep her here until you come.
Zatrzymamy ją tutaj do waszego przyjazdu.
Do you know what you're saying?
Nie wiesz, o czym mówisz.
If she realizes you still have your human brain,
Jeśli zobaczy, że masz ludzki mózg, bez wahania cię zaatakuje!
What?
Co?
She's a hundred meters away.
Jest sto metrów od nas.
Hurry! Get out of there!
Szybko stamtąd uciekajcie!
Okay!
Dobrze!
I'll follow the cape and head to the town where you are now!
Będę szedł wybrzeżem w twoją stronę!
Shinichi, I'm detecting one parasite.
Shinichi, wyczuwam pasożyta.
One?
Jednego?
That must be Uda-san.
To pewnie Uda-san.
Hurry up! She'll catch up to us!
Szybko! Dogoni nas!
This is the best I can do!
Szybciej nie dam rady!
Looks like she's able to maximize the potential of the human body.
Ona chyba w pełni wykorzystuje potencjał ludzkiego ciała.
We don't stand a chance against her.
Nie mamy z nią szans.
-Let's make a break for it! -We can't!
- Uciekajmy! - Nie możemy!
Shinichi-kun and Migi will be here soon.
Shinichi-kun i Migi zaraz tu będą.
We have to work together to beat her!
Musimy razem ją pokonać!
Then, go that way!
To idź tam.
We'll have a better chance there.
Tam mamy większą szansę.
Shinichi.
Shinichi.
You can sense the other one?
Wyczuwasz drugiego?
No. I'm tired.
Nie. Jestem zmęczony.
You've got to be kidding me!
Chyba żartujesz!
I can't stay awake any longer.
Zaraz zasnę.
Wake up, Migi!
Obudź się! Pozwolisz, żeby Uda-san i jego pasożyt zginęli?
At least, I can leave you this.
Dam ci chociaż to.
Hey!
Hej!
If you can, run.
Jeśli możesz, uciekaj.
Choose your own survival.
Musisz ratować siebie.
It'll be fine.
Poradzę sobie.
If I can join forces with Uda-san and Parasite…
Połączę siły z Uda-sanem i Parasite’em…
Hey, the path ends here.
Koniec ścieżki!
Isn't this bad?
Niedobrze, prawda?
No, even if she catches up to us,
Dobrze, bo jeśli nas tu dogoni,
you and Shinichi can flank her here.
ty i Shinichi ją otoczycie.
You're the second one I've met whose brain is intact.
Drugi, którego mózg nie został przejęty.
But to me, you are just a hindrance.
Dla mnie jesteś tylko przeszkodą.
I will finish you now.
Zabiję cię.
So this is what the "finished product" that we're supposed to be looks like!
A więc tak powinien wyglądać produkt końcowy!
Where?
Gdzie?
Where is she?
Gdzie ona jest?
I… I'm going to die!
Zaraz umrę!
You are pathetic.
Jesteś żałosny.
Compared to my host that has unified with me,
W porównaniu z moim gospodarzem
the human that you reside in is sluggish.
twój człowiek jest niedołężny.
Yeah, tell me about it.
Co ty nie powiesz?
Not to mention, his breathing's so uneven that even I'm getting tired.
Ma taki nierówny oddech, że nawet ja się męczę.
But this chick's attacks follow a pretty simple pattern,
Ta laska atakuje w prosty sposób.
as if she's only targeting one spot on our body.
Wybiera tylko jeden punkt na ciele.
This fight is over.
Koniec walki.
Die now.
Giń.
In cases like yours, when it's unclear how far the parasite's influence reaches,
Gdy nie wiemy, jaki zasięg ma pasożyt, jak w twoim przypadku,
destroying the heart is the most effective approach.
najlepiej jest zniszczyć serce.
I guessed as much.
Domyśliłem się.
Another one?
Kolejny?
But something's not right.
Ale coś tu nie gra.
The signal's too weak, as if the parasite is asleep.
Sygnał jest słaby, jakby pasożyt spał.
Why?
Jak to?
I killed you!
Zabiłam cię!
Was my aim off?
Nie trafiłam?
No, that's impossible.
To niemożliwe.
How did you survive getting stabbed in the heart?
Jak przeżyłeś taki cios w serce?
I suppose I should've cut your head off as well.
Powinnam była odciąć ci głowę.
This is cruel.
To okrutne.
Even the voice is the same.
Nawet głos ma taki sam.
I won't waste any time killing you!
Nie będę tracił czasu i cię zabiję!
That's right.
Dobrze.
Come!
Chodź tu!
A monster should look like one!
Wyglądaj jak potwór!
I'll kill you, too.
Ciebie też zabiję.
"Too"?
„Też”?
Then, is Uda-san…
Czyli Uda-san…
His right hand's signal is weak.
Sygnał z prawej ręki jest słaby.
It's as though it's hibernating.
Jakby hibernował.
If that's true, then what can one lone human possibly accomplish?
Jeśli to prawda, to co może ten człowiek?
He evaded my attacks?
Zrobił unik?
No, humans don't have that kind of agility.
Ludzie nie mają takiej sprawności.
Impossible!
Niemożliwe!
I see it!
Widzę to!
I can see each move she makes!
Widzę jej każdy ruch!
It's totally different from when I fought A!
Jest inaczej niż wtedy, gdy walczyłem z X!
Now, I see!
Widzę!
When they move, they're morphing at incredible speeds!
Gdy się ruszają, łączą się z ogromną prędkością.
Inconceivable!
Nie wierzę!
Uda-san!
Uda-san!
He was the only one…
Tylko on…
The only one in the world who could understand!
Tylko on mógł to zrozumieć!
Damn you!
Do diabła z tobą!
How?
Jak?
How can he move so fast?
Jak może się tak szybko ruszać?
The neck.
Szyja.
Just aim for the neck up!
Celuj od szyi w górę!
I'll kill you!
Zabiję cię!
Now! Without a moment's delay!
Teraz! Bez chwili wahania!
He can't be human!
To nie może być człowiek!
He's not human!
Nie jest człowiekiem!
Mom! Mom, I'm going to…
Mamo! Zaraz…
I'm going to hack that monster out of you right now!
Zaraz wypędzę z ciebie tego potwora!
Shit!
Cholera!
Die.
Giń.
Uda-san!
Uda-san!
This isn't your mom, of course.
To nie była twoja mama.
But…
Ale…
I don't think you should be the one to finish her.
to nie ty powinieneś ją zabijać.
Why?
Jak?
Why are you also alive?
Jakim cudem ty też żyjesz?
I figured out your pattern of attack.
Przejrzałem twój atak.
You always went right for our heart,
Od razu uderzasz w serce.
so I shifted the positions of our heart and vital organs
Więc zmieniłem położenie serca i ważnych organów
right before you struck.
tuż przed twoim atakiem.
Mom.
Mamo.
It's over.
Już po wszystkim.
It's over now.
To koniec.
Thank you for your hospitality.
Dziękuję za gościnę.
Goodbye.
Do widzenia.
Hey, I'll see you to the hospital!
Odprowadzę cię do szpitala!
Did you finish what you needed to do?
Zrobiłeś to, co miałeś zrobić?
Yeah, I did.
Tak.
Hey, come back to do some sightseeing next time.
Wróć tu kiedyś na zwiedzanie.
No, I don't think I'll ever come back.
Nie, raczej tu nie wrócę.
No!
Nie!
I mean… Just sometime.
Może kiedyś?
It can be a long time from now.
Może minąć dużo czasu.
Okay.
Dobrze.
Goodbye.
Żegnaj.
I hope you'll understand when I say… Um, how should I put this?
Mam nadzieję, że zrozumiesz… Jak to powiedzieć?
I just want you to believe me when I say…
Chcę, żebyś mi uwierzył.
that right until the end, no, even now, your mom loves you.
Do samego końca… Nie, nawet teraz twoja mama cię kocha.
And I love you and Mom, too.
A ja kocham ciebie i twoją mamę.
Okay.
Jasne.
Dad, I want to ask you something.
Tato, powiedz mi coś.
About your dream.
O twoim śnie.
Um…
Ten…
In the nightmare you had,
Ten koszmar…
No, it all happened so fast.
Nie, to stało się bardzo szybko.
I see.
Rozumiem.
Shinichi?
Shinichi?
NISHI FUKUYAMA STATION - SOUTH EXIT
DWORZEC NISHI FUKUYAMA
It's him.
To on.
He's close!
Jest blisko!
Izumi-kun?
Izumi-kun?
Izumi-kun!
Izumi-kun!
He's back!
Wrócił!
Hey.
Hejka.
Next time, "Freezing Point."
Następny odcinek: „Punkt zamarzania”.